[Speaker 1] The cultivation of ornamental plants broadly classifies into potted nursery plants and flowers which are used commercially and for ornamental purposes in the households.
[Speaker 1] These are grown in various structures where we call it as the poly house, which is a protected structure, we call it as a protected cultivation.
[Speaker 1] And a smaller version of it is called the tunnel house, again, it is a poly house structure.
[Speaker 1] And the third one is called the shade net, which is nothing but a net protecting the insects with a lot of ventilation for air flow and sunlight.
[Speaker 1] And the fourth one is the open field cultivation.
[Speaker 1] We will see all these four in detail.
[Speaker 1] I will explain each one of them in detail.
[Speaker 1] So let's start with the poly house structures first.
[Speaker 1] Poly house structure is again called as I said is the high-tech cultivation method.
[Speaker 1] It is pretty expensive compared to all these four types of cultivation.
[Speaker 1] The government is funding for this type of poly house structures construction with subsidies from missions like NHB National Horticulture Board and NHM which is the National Horticulture Mission.
[Speaker 1] A bit of difference also I will explain here, maybe it will be useful for you in getting in touch with touch based with the government for the subsidies.
[Speaker 1] NHB, it operates from the central and the loan processing happens in this way.
[Speaker 1] One will have to identify the land, will have to identify the crop, prepare a project report, present it to the bank, the funding bank, and then get an approval from the bank.
[Speaker 1] Later, fill up a form with the National Horticulture Board, submit it stating the same report that this is the project that we are going to take it.
[Speaker 1] We will submit those documents to the government explaining that this is the project report and this is the projected income out of the project and the government approves with a work order.
[Speaker 1] Once that work order is done, the bank receives that work order letter and within a period of a month's time, a 50% subsidy of the amount is funded back into the loan account and thereby the expenses what you have incurred by taking up the loan goes down by 50%.
[Speaker 1] This is the back end model.
[Speaker 1] The other model is we will have to keep on paying the principal loan amount up till the principal loan amount is equal to the 50% subsidy.